报告 一辆黑色阿尔法罗密欧
正尾随一辆灰色阿斯顿马丁跑车
双方发生枪战
(意大利 锡耶纳)
该下车了
It's time to get out.
《007系列之大破量子危机》
别流血致死
Don't bleed to death.
你好 米丘 邦德
Hello, Mitchell. Bond.
美国佬一定不会很高兴
The Americans are gonna be none too pleased about this.
他们不是找到勒齐弗了吗?
I promised them Le Chiffre, and they got Le Chiffre.
他们找到他的尸体
They got his body.
要他的灵魂 得找一个神父
If they'd wanted his soul, they should have made a deal with a priest.
他有没有招什么?
Has he said anything?
没有
No.
我去查看周围
I'm going to check the perimeter, ma'am.
你看起来很累
You look like hell.
几时睡过觉?
When's the last time you slept?
尤瑟夫 卡毕拉 维丝普的男友
Vesper's boyfriend, Yusef Kabira, the one who was abducted in Morocco,
他在摩洛哥被绑架 她想救他
the one she was trying to save.
他的尸体被冲到伊比萨海滩
His body was washed up on a beach in lbiza.
凶手要我们相信脸被鱼咬成这样
We're meant to believe the fish did that to his face.
他口袋有皮夹和身份证
His wallet and ID were in his pocket.
太刻意了 是啊
Well, that's convenient. Quite.
我用他在女友家留下的一撮头发
Which is why I did a DNA check
进行DNA检验
on a lock of his hair found in Vesper's apartment.
这不是他
It's not him.
一撮头发?
A lock of his hair?
没想到维丝普这么念旧
I wouldn't have thought Vesper the sentimental type.
知人知面不知心 对吧?
Well, we never really know anyone, do we?
不过我得知道
But I do need to know, Bond.
我得知道我能信任你
I need to know that I can trust you.
你不信任我?
And you don't?
只有冷血杀手...
Well, it'd be a pretty cold bastard
才不会为了心爱的人报仇
who didn't want revenge for the death of someone he loved.
你不必担心我
You don't have to worry about me.
我不会追杀他 他不重要
I'm not gonna go chasing him. He's not important.
她也不重要
And neither was she.
安全
It's clear, ma'am.
谢了 米丘　来吧
Thanks, Mitchell. Shall we?
你说不说你为谁工作?
Are you gonna tell us who you work for?
我一直很想见你
I was always very interested to meet you.
维丝普经常提起你
I'd heard so much about you from Vesper.
真可惜 要是她没自杀
The real shame is that if she hadn't killed herself,
你也会替我们做事
we would have had you, too.
你为了她什么都肯做
I think you would have done anything for her.
这里不是英国 天晓得明天你会在哪里
Well, you know you're not in Britain, and God knows where you'll be tomorrow.
所以你会说出...
Which should tell you that eventually
你替谁做事
you will tell us about the people you work with,
你愈不说 就会愈痛苦
and the longer it takes, the more painful we'll make it.
你们对我们真的一无所知
You really don't know anything about us.
真有趣 因为我们以为
It's so amusing because we are on the other side,
你们和中情局都在监视我们
thinking, "The Ml6, the CIA, they're looking over our shoulders.
监听我们的谈话
"They're listening to our conversations."
你们却不知道我们的存在
And the truth is you don't even know we exist.
现在知道了 我们学得很快
Well, we do now, Mr. White, and we're quick learners.
是吗? 那么你们应该要知道...
Oh, really? Well, then, the first thing you should know about us
到处都有我们的人
is that we have people everywhere.
对吧?
Am I right?
(伦敦)
有线索吗?
Anything?
克雷格 米丘替我做事八年了
Craig Mitchell worked for me for eight years.
每年都通过安全检查和测谎
He passed a full security check and lie detector test every year.
连一点证据都没留下来
Didn't leave so much as a scrap of paper to explain any of it.
八年啊! 其中五年还是我的贴身保镖
Eight years! Five as my personal bodyguard.
我只找到这玩意 还有三件
I found this and three other bloody Christmas presents
我送他的圣诞礼物
I bought him about the house.
他应该不抽烟
I don't think he smoked.
你杀死他
And you had to kill him.
而不是带他回来问话
Couldn't bring him in for questioning so that we might actually learn something.
有人说到处都有他们的人 你一定认为是夸大其词
When someone says we got people everywhere, you expect it to be hyperbole.
很多人都会这么说 像是花店老板
Lots of people say that. Florists use that expression.
并不代表他们派人埋伏在这里
Doesn't mean that they've got somebody working for them inside the bloody room.
这是什么鬼组织?
What the hell is this organization, Bond?
他们遍布四处我们却无所知?
How can they be everywhere and we know nothing about them?
我猜怀特消失不见了 没错
I assume we found no trace of White. No.
你在门口看到的探员死了
The agent guarding the door in the garage was dead
就在你在楼梯处经过他之前
before you passed him on the stairs.
我看到他? 老天爷!
I passed him on the stairs? Christ!
一定是被米丘杀死的
Mitchell must have killed him when he went out to check the perimeter.
你能活着算是幸运
You're lucky to be here.
你认为怀特还活着吗?
Do you think White's still alive?
是的 什么事?
Yes, I do. What is it?
克雷格 米丘 45岁 没有家人
Craig Mitchell, 45 years old.
经常捐款给慈善机构
No living family. Gave generously to charity.
别说你只知道这么多
Tell me you know more than that.
我们查过他皮夹和家里的钞票
Our moneymen went through every bill in Mitchell's wallet and house.
他有多少钱?
How much did he have?
不到一百英镑
Less than 100 pounds,
欧元和美金也差不多
and about the same in euros and dollars.
对不起
Excuse me. Excuse me, ma'am.
我们进行过完全的分析
We've done a complete forensic analysis
每张钞票和其来源
of every note and its traceable history.
没心情听
Not in the mood.
您先请
After you.
米丘皮夹的这张钞票很有趣
This particular note from Mitchell's wallet may be of interest.
扫描中
Scanning.
我们拦截勒齐弗的非法交易时...
We introduced tagged bills into Le Chiffre's money-laundering operation
在钞票上面做了记号
by intercepting illegal payoffs.
透过他的银行帐户追踪来源
We traced money through several of his bank accounts around the world.
这不成证据 钞票流通得很快
That's pretty thin. At the rate money changes hands,
搞不好我也有做记号的钞票
you could probably find a tenner in my wallet with a tag.
没错 一张钞票可能是巧合
That's true, ma'am. A single bill could be a coincidence,
可是一整叠呢?
but what about a whole stack?
这些钞票的编号和米丘的一样
These bills, from the same series as Mitchell's,
刚刚在海地的太子港被发现
were just scanned at a bank in Port-au-Prince, Haiti,
被存进史莱特先生的帐户
deposited in the account of a Mr. Slate.
说来听听
Impress me.
史先生今早从英国返回太子港
We have a Mr. Edmund Slate returning to Port-au-Prince from Heathrow this morning.
入境卡显示他住在迪萨利旅馆
His entry documents have him staying at the Hotel Dessalines.
325号房
He's in room 325.
(海地 太子港)
- 谢谢　- 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
(迪萨利旅馆)
325号房有留言吗?
Do you have any messages for 325?
没有 只有稍早替您...
No, sir. The only message was about the briefcase
寄放的公事包
that was delivered earlier.
您要寄在柜台吗?
Did you want us to continue holding it?
不 我要拿走
No. No, I'll take that now.
好的
Yes, sir.
- 谢谢　- 不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
上车!
Get in!
什么?
What?
上车
Get in.
好吧
All right.
你迟到了
You're late.
我临时跟人开会
I got pulled into a meeting.
跟谁?
Who with?
怀特先生的朋友
A friend of Mr. White's.
我不认识他
Don't think I know him.
怪了
It's funny.
你长得跟我想的不同
You don't look at all like I expected.
是吗? 你以为我长什么样?
Really? What were you expecting?
没想到地质学家长得这么...
I didn't think geologists looked so...
怎样?
So?
你的朋友吗?
A friend of yours?
我没有朋友
I don't have any friends.
给我让开! 闪边!
Get out of the way! Move!
我们还没谈好价钱
We didn't settle on a price.
出个价吧
Make me an offer.
待会儿边喝酒边谈 如何?
We can work it out later, over drinks.
多明尼克有找你麻烦吗?
Dominic didn't give you any trouble, did he?
没有
No.
这是什么鬼东西?
What the hell is this?
有人想要暗杀你
I think someone wants to kill you.
好心没好报
That wasn't very nice.
你应该射杀她的
You were supposed to shoot her.
我没射中
Well, I missed.
打给邦德
Get Bond.
他在哪里?
Where is he now?
接近港口
Approaching the docks, Kings Quay.
连线中　坦纳
Connecting. Tanner.
电话通了　问他史莱特的事
I've got Bond. Ask him about Slate.
史莱特怎么样?
She wants to know about Slate.
他是步死棋
Tell her Slate was a dead end.
史莱特是步死棋
Slate was a dead end.
通话断线
Connection terminated.
该死 他杀死了他
Damn him. He killed him.
让她进去
哇! 哇! 哇! 哇!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
敢碰我 我就折断你的手
Touch me and I'll break your wrist.
有访客 别烦我 我在忙
卡蜜儿?
Camille.
很高兴看到你
How nice to see you.
没想到我还活着?
Alive, you mean?
我就知道我们不该上床
I knew we shouldn't have slept together.
我开始喜欢上你了
I think I'm starting to like you.
你是真的想要杀死我
So you did just try and have me killed.
我想到再也见不到你...
And that made me very sad
就难过
thinking I would never see you again.
幸好你没死
But here you are.
多明尼克 我想帮你
Damn it, Dominic! I was trying to help you.
我想替你逮到内鬼
I was trying to uncover a leak.
你却派人暗杀我?
And you, you sent someone to kill me?
别把我当成傻瓜
Please don't talk to me like I'm stupid!
你这样子很丑
It's unattractive.
来 我给你看样东西
Come. I wanna show you something.
来吧
Come.
我最不喜欢朋友...
There's nothing that makes me more uncomfortable
在我背后说闲话
than friends talking behind my back.
就好像...
It feels like
蚂蚁爬满我全身
ants under my skin.
我一直都是这样
It's been that way forever.
我记得15岁那年
I remember when I was 15,
我偷偷暗恋我妈的钢琴学生
I had a crush on one of my mother's piano students.
很不巧 我听到她说我的坏话
Somehow I overheard her saying very nasty things about me.
我气到不行
I got so angry.
于是拿了一个熨斗...
I took an iron.
那是他吗?
Is that him?
我...
I...
我只跟他通过电话
We only spoke on the phone.
真可惜 他是最好的地质学家
It's such a shame because he's one of my best geologists.
他说你想买一些资料
He said you asked to buy information.
他打给我想卖我一些资料
No. He called me and offered to sell me information.
要是我说谎干嘛回来?
Why would I come back here if I was lying?
因为你爱我
Because you love me.
我是为了你
I was doing it for you.
阻止他出卖你
To stop him from betraying you.
有件事比你向我说谎更让我生气
You know what burns more than all your bullshit?
我一直觉得你跟我上床是为了...
Is that I always got the feeling that you were only sleeping with me
接近马卓诺将军
to get to General Medrano.
那是他吗?
Is that him?
你很了解被放逐的独裁者
You know how these deposed dictators are,
总是没有安全感
jealous of their safety.
留下来
Stick around.
我把他介绍给你
I'll introduce you.
请你把这个...
Do you see the girl that just walked in here?
交给刚才那个女生
Could you give her that? Tell her to call me.
他要干嘛?
他要她打给他
(寰宇出口商)
(全球定位系统信号追踪)
(连接安全管道 绿色星球)
(目标确认)
这里是寰宇出口商...
You've reached Universal Exports.
眼下办公室关着的
Our offices are currently closed.
下次聪明点
你可以替我办到这件事?
And you can do all this for me?
看看我们把这国家搞成怎样
Well, look at what we did to this country.
海地人选一个神父当总统
The Haitians elect a priest
把最低工资从38分调到1元
who decides to raise the minimum wage from 38 cents to $1 a day.
哇!
Whoa!
虽然不多 但是已经让...
It's not a lot, but it's enough to upset the corporations
制造T恤和跑鞋的工厂很不爽
who were here making T-shirts and running shoes.
于是他们找我们
So they called us,
我们则替他们改变现状
and we facilitated a change.
不同的是...
The difference is,
我的国家并不是加勒比海的一个小岛
my country's not some flyspeck in the middle of the Caribbean.
不过我们已经开始造成政治不安
But we've already begun destabilizing the government.
我们会提供私人保全
We'll supply the private security.
也会贿赂重要的官员
We'll pay off the right officials,
我们也说服26个国家...
and we have 26 countries ready to officially recognize
正式和全新的玻利维亚政府建交
your new Bolivian government.
你要夺回你的国家
You want your country back.
我的组织可以在一周内办到
My organization can give it to you within the week.
看来你很忙
You've been busy.
你要什么做为回报?
And in return you want what?
一片沙漠
A desert.
这地方
This part.
那地方一文不值
This land is worthless. Oh.
你算是捡到便宜啰
So you're getting a great deal.
你们在那里挖不到石油
You won't find oil there.
每个人都试过
Everyone has tried.
也许吧 也许没有
Maybe, maybe not.
不过找到什么都是我们的
But we own whatever we find.
你认识埃内斯托 蒙特斯吗?
Did you know Ernesto Montes?
他当年权力很大
A very powerful man in his day.
他有一个很美的俄国妻子
He had a beautiful Russian wife.
一名舞者
A dancer.
他女儿替我做事
Well, his daughter works for me.
或者是...曾经
Or did.
她很漂亮
She's lovely,
不过她不像她母亲
but I don't see the resemblance.
把她当成这笔交易的...
Why don't you consider her
额外好处
as something to sweeten the deal?
完事后一定要把她解决掉
Just promise me to drop her over the side when you're done.
卡蜜儿 马卓诺将军
Camille, General Medrano.
我认识你的家人
很遗憾 见过他们死前最后一面
愿望实现有时候不是好事
Be careful what you wish for, my dear.
玩得开心
Have fun, you two.
你在干嘛?
What the hell are you doing?
不客气! 白痴! 带我回去!
You're welcome! You idiot! Take me back!
也许晚一点吧
You know, maybe I'll do that later.
你不是格林的手下
You're not one of Greene's.
多明尼克 格林?
Dominic Greene?
趴下!
Get down!
我来掌舵
Give me the wheel!
你来导航
Navigate!
向左
Left!
你在干嘛? 抓紧了!
What are you doing? Hold on!
趴下!
Get down!
不好意思
Excuse me.
谢谢你 她晕船
Thank you. She's seasick.
是邦德
It's Bond.
接邦德
Connect Bond.
接听　请说
Connecting 007. Yes?
查缉对象: 多明尼克 格林
Name check, Dominic Greene.
G-R-E-E-N-E 格林
G-R-E-E-N-E.
还有其他的资料吗?
I might need a little more than that.
很多人叫这个名字
There are a lot of Dominic Greenes.
有社会安全码
Do you have a social security
或护照号码? 没有
or passport number? No.
搜寻法国情报局资料库
Scanning DGSE databases.
查到什么? 搜寻KGB资料库
Anything? Scanning KGB databases.
有没有查到什么? 叫她听电话
Do you have anything? Will you put her on, please?
我在听 史莱特怎么了?
I am on, Bond. What happened to Slate?
那是过去式
I'm not dwelling on the past.
别管他
I don't think you should, either.
你杀了他
You killed him.
最接近的结果 多明尼克 格林 绿色星球执行长
Largest hit, Dominic Greene, CEO of Greene Planet.
那是一家水电能源公司
It's a utility company,
不过他也从事慈善事业
but Greene's been doing a lot of philanthropic work,
购买土地做为生态保护区
buying up large tracts of land for ecological preserves.
照片传过去了
You should be getting his picture now.
没错 就是他
Yep, that's him.
他的电脑系统装了防火墙
I'm afraid there's a firewall around his other corporate holdings,
查不到其它资料
so we have no other information.
帮我接美国
Get me the Americans.
接线中
Connecting.
请说
Go ahead.
多明尼克 格林 绿色星球
Interest in Dominic Greene, Greene Planet.
马上替您转接
Transferring you now.
格雷戈里 毕恩在线上
Hold for Gregory Beam, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是格雷戈里 毕恩
Hi, this is Gregory Beam, ma'am.
你好 毕恩先生
Hello, Mr. Beam.
抱歉让您久等 我们对格林先生没兴趣
I'm so sorry to keep you waiting. We have no interest in Mr. Greene.
谢谢你
Thank you, Mr. Beam.
连线中止
Connection terminated.
他对格林兴趣很大
He's a person of extreme interest.
但他说他没兴趣... 我一提到格林...
But he just said that he wasn't... Tanner, I asked about the man
就被转接到中情局南美洲的主管
and she transferred me to the section chief of South America.
这代表他们一定在调查他
How would she know to do that if they weren't tracking him?
你正接近一座机场
Bond, we have your location as approaching an airfield.
- 格林准备起飞吗? - 对
- Is Greene on the move? - Yeah.
飞机代码: G-0CSC
I've got a tail number, Golf-Zero-Charlie-Sierra-Charlie.
把目的地给我
Get me a destination.
前往奥地利柏根市的私人包机
It's a private charter going to Bregenz, Austria,
马上就要起飞了
leaving immediately.
授权让007使用喷射机
Tanner, authorize a charter for 007.
邦德 拜托你留些活口来问线索
And, Bond, if you could avoid killing every possible lead,
那样最好不过了
it would be deeply appreciated.
遵命 我会尽力
Yes, ma'am. I'll do my best.
连线中断
Connection terminated.
你说过很多次了
I've heard that before.
- 你好 - 嗨
- Hello. - Hi.
欢迎登机
Ah. Welcome aboard.
请坐
Come. Have a seat.
天啊
Jeez.
对不起
Sorry.
还要飞多久?
How much longer?
我们有共识吗?
So do we have an understanding?
当然了 我们不会阻止玻利维亚的政变
Uh, yeah. We do nothing to stop a coup in Bolivia,
条件是新政府
and in exchange, the new government
挖到石油要给美国
gives America the lease to any oil found.
没问题
If it's oil you want.
你们没挖到钻石吧?
Well, you didn't find diamonds, did you?
在地底钻洞能避免被雷达发现
Drilling underground, you kept off everybody's radar for a very long time,
但买那么多输油管
but you can't buy that much piping
一定有人起疑
without somebody getting curious.
我们必须确认找到石油
We'll have to verify the find.
我根本就没承认有这件事 如果有 免费送给你们
I'm not even admitting there is one. You are getting this for free.
委内瑞拉 巴西 现在又是玻利维亚
Venezuela, Brazil, now Bolivia.
美国忙着应付中东的局势
With you tied up in the Middle East,
南美洲国家像多米诺骨牌一样的垮台
South America is falling like dominoes.
你们不会让共产党...把国家资源提供给人民吧?
You don't need another Marxist giving national resources to the people, do you?
我们不知道有政变...
Well, we can hardly be expected to do something
能做什么?
about a coup we know nothing about.
有人在烦我
And I have a pest.
你看
This.
知道那是谁吗?
You have any idea who that is?
抱歉
Sorry.
英国情报局的詹姆斯 邦德
It's James Bond, British Secret Service.
我怎么会没认出他来?
I don't know how I could have missed that.
我要你帮我把他除掉
I will need you to get rid of him for me.
好 没问题
Yeah. That's not gonna be a problem.
(奥地利 柏根市)
你明知道格林是个大坏蛋
You know who Greene is
却偏偏要和他打交道
and you wanna put us in bed with him.
你是在开玩笑吧 是吗?
You are kidding, right?
是啊 我们应该和好人打交道
Yeah. You're right. We should just deal with nice people.
我要知道你属于这团队
I need to know you're on the team, Felix.
而且很重视你的工作
I need to know you value your career.
(追踪中)
(艺人入口)
多明尼克 格林
Dominic Greene.
很高兴见到你　你好吗?
Good to see you. How are you?
很好 谢谢
Good. Thank you.
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen.
歌剧《托斯卡》即将开始 敬请入座
Tonight's performance ofTosca will begin shortly. Please take your seats.
马卓诺将军还要什么?
What else does General Medrano require?
加拿大情报局有消息吗?
Anything further from Canadian intelligence?
我们待会再说
We'll discuss that later.
我们还需要多少输油管?
How much more pipeline do we need?
最好是两千公里
Ideally, 2,000 kilometers.
有人反对吗?
Are there any objections?
不反对
No.
我不反对
Not here.
我也不反对
No objections.
把钱从西伯利亚帐户转出
Transfer the funds from our Siberian holdings.
搞定
Done.
美国的立场是什么?
Where do the Americans stand?
只要他们能分一杯羹 才不会在乎另一个独裁者
Well, the CIA doesn't care about another dictator as long as they get their end.
要是他们发现被骗呢?
But when they find out that they've been duped?
我会处理的
I'm working on that.
提亚计划会浪费量子集团的时间
I'm still not sure that the Tierra Project is the best use of Quantum's time.
也许应该打加拿大的主意
Perhaps we should shift our focus to the Canadian.
这是世上最珍贵的资源
This is the world's most precious resource.
我们要尽可能握为己有
We need to control as much of it as we can.
玻利维亚是第一优先
Bolivia must be top priority.
我能岔个话吗?
Can I offer an opinion?
你们应该找更好的地方会面
I really think you people should find a better place to meet.
你们想去哪里?
Where do you think you're going?
谢谢你们
Thank you.
不是每个人都爱看歌剧
Well, Tosca isn't for everyone.
把枪放下
Drop it.
你替谁做事?
So who are you working for?
滚蛋
Piss off.
把带来的东西丢掉 我们曝光了
Get rid of anything we brought with us. We've been compromised.
我问你你替谁做事
I asked you who you were working for.
他是自己人吗?
Is he one of ours?
不是
No.
那你就不应该看着我
Then he shouldn't be looking at me.
帮我接M夫人
Get me M.
您的电话　谢了
It's your line. Thanks.
接过来
Connect call.
接通中
Connecting Tanner.
查出照片的身份
We've ID'd the pictures.
给我看
Show me.
格雷戈 卡拉科夫 前任总理
Gregor Karakov, former minister,
现在拥有西伯利亚大部分的矿场
now owns most of the mines in Siberia,
莫西 萨里夫 前以色列情报局 现在是电信业大亨
Moishe Soref, former Mossad, now telecom giant,
盖伊 海恩 英国首相的特使
and Guy Haines, special envoy to the Prime Minister.
打给邦德
Get Bond.
还有一件事
There's something else.
邦德射杀海恩的保镖 然后把他推下屋顶
It appears Bond shot Haines' bodyguard and threw him off a roof.
你在哪里? 拿到我拍的照片吗?
Where are you? Did you get my pictures?
这算是问话吗? 你能证明这些人有关系吗?
Was this a conversation? Can you link these people?
你的声音好像有点紧张
Is that stress in your voice?
我要你回来做简报
I need you to come in and debrief.
我没有时间　邦德
I don't have time. Bond,
你在柏根市杀死一个人
You killed a man in Bregenz.
我已经尽量约束自己了
I did my best not to.
你射杀他 然后把他推下屋顶
You shot him at point blank and threw him off a roof.
哪一点都不算约束自己
I'd hardly call that showing restraint,
尤其是他隶属英国调查局
especially since he was a member of Special Branch.
他在保护谁?
So who was he guarding?
你杀死英国调查局干员
Bond, are you missing the fact that you killed a member of Special Branch?
我要你回来
I need you to come in.
我也想 不过我得找到想杀死你的人
And I would, but right now I need to find the man who tried to kill you.
回去睡觉吧
Go back to sleep.
通话结束
Connection terminated.
限制邦德的行动 取消他的信用卡
Restrict Bond's movements. Cancel his cards.
注销他护照 所有的
Put an alert on his passports. All of them.
查出关于海恩的一切
And I want to know everything we don't know about Haines.
遵命
Yes, ma'am.
还有...小心你该信任谁
And, Tanner, be careful who you trust with this.
希望你比我更会看人
Hopefully, you're a better judge of character than I am.
您要跟您朋友去玻利维亚吗?
You want to follow your friends to La Paz, Bolivia?
是的
Please.
哦
Oh.
抱歉 这张卡无效
I'm sorry, sir, but this doesn't work.
您有另一张卡吗?
Do you have another card?
没有
No.
请你帮我一个忙
Could you do me a favor?
等一下你会接到电话
You're gonna get a phone call in a minute.
请你告诉对方我要去开罗
Would you mind telling them I'm headed for Cairo?
我很乐意　谢谢
I'd be happy to. Thank you.
(意大利 塔拉莫内)
马西斯
Mathis.
你想干嘛?
What do you want?
你是来道歉的吗?
Come to apologize?
你知道吗
You know, Mathis,
你很适合退休
I think retirement suits you.
别给他倒酒
None for him.
抱歉 他今天心情不好
Sorry. He's in a bad mood today.
他害我被严刑拷打 你还要给他喝酒?
反正你买的酒都是便宜货
你被证明无辜后 还得到这栋豪宅
所以其实是你欠他人情 不是吗?
贾玛 去做日光浴吧
我需要护照和信用卡
I need a passport and matching credit cards.
英国情报局缺货吗?
And Ml6 ran out of plastic?
奇怪的是 现在我只能信任你
Well, oddly, right now, you're the only person I think I can trust.
这是很奇怪
That is odd.
我猜一个人年轻的时候...
But I guess when one's young,
很容易分别是非对错
it seems very easy to distinguish between right and wrong.
老了以后就比较难
But as one gets older, it becomes more difficult.
坏人和好人都分不清楚
The villains and the heroes get all mixed up.
很遗憾听到维丝普的死
I was sorry to hear about Vesper.
我认为她很爱你
I think she loved you.
呃
Mmm.
直到她出卖我那一刻
Right up until the moment she betrayed me.
她为了你而死
She died for you.
你到底为什么来找我?
Why did you really want to see me?
我需要一些资料
I need some information.
啊
Ah.
你的朋友是狠角色 这家伙是主使
You have some hard friends. This man is some kind of facilitator.
专门干坏事 绝不留下证据
Fingers in many pies, and they don't leave any prints.
这些人是一伙的?
These men were together?
他们在买输油管
They're buying up oil pipeline.
被称之为提亚计划 你知道吗?
Something called the Tierra Project. Do you know it?
把这些销毁
Destroy these.
他是海恩 你不认识他?
That's Guy Haines. You don't know him?
我应该认识他吗?
Should I?
我猜不是吧 你不像我保密保了这么久
I suppose not. You haven't been keeping secrets as long as I have.
他非常低调
He keeps a very low profile,
不过他是英国首相的重要顾问
but he's one of the Prime Minister's closest advisors.
俗话说知己知彼 百战百胜
Well, they say you're judged by the strength of your enemies.
你知道玻利维亚的事吗?
Do you know anything about Bolivia?
我在南美洲驻守了七年
I was stationed in South America for seven years.
你在那里有线人吗?
Well, do you have some contacts there?
有一些
A few.
你想知道什么?
What do you want to know?
跟我来
Come with me.
我要你抚摸我...
睡不着?
You can't sleep?
来杯酒吗?
May I fix you a drink, sir?
你在喝什么?
What are you drinking?
不知道 我在喝什么?
I don't know. What am I drinking?
三份琴酒 一份伏特加 半份的...
Three measures of Gordon's gin, one of vodka, half of...
莉兰酒　莉兰酒不是苦艾酒
Kina Lillet. Kina Lillet, which is not Vermouth,
加入冰块均匀搅拌
shaken well until it is ice-cold,
接着放上一片柠檬薄片
then served with a large thin slice of lemon peel.
他喝了六杯
Six of them.
好酒量
That's impressive.
很好喝 试试看
They're good. You should have one.
不了 只会让我睡不着
No, it'll just keep me awake.
你为什么睡不着?
So what's keeping you awake?
我在想你为什么跟我来?
I was wondering why you came with me.
承认自己错了需要一点勇气
It takes something to admit you were wrong.
你要安眠药吗?
You want a sleeping pill?
不要
No.
止痛药? 不要
Pain pill? No.
我什么药都有
I have pills for everything.
有些药能让你长高
Some make you taller.
有些药能让你忘记
Some make you forget.
我要去试着睡觉
I'm going to try and get some sleep.
好主意
Good idea.
(玻利维亚 拉巴斯)
谢谢
Thank you.
我是费姿 领事馆的工作人员
Mr. Bond, my name is Fields. I'm from the consulate.
看出来了
Well, of course you are.
你在领事馆做什么?
And what do you do at the consulate, Fields?
这不重要
That's not important.
我奉命把你...
My orders are to turn you around
送上飞机回到伦敦
and put you on the first plane back to London.
包括我的朋友马西斯吗?
Do those orders include my friend Mathis?
抱歉 我不认识你
I'm sorry, I don't know who you are.
你才离开没多久就被忘记了
You see that? Gone such a short time and already forgotten.
你故意这么说让我难过
You're just saying that to hurt me.
邦德先生 这是最高指令
Mr. Bond, these orders come from the highest possible authority.
下一班到伦敦的班机是几时?
Taxi. Fields, when is the next flight to London?
明天早上
Tomorrow morning.
那我们还有整晚的时间
Well then, we have all night.
如果你想逃跑 我会逮捕你
If you attempt to flee, I will arrest you,
把你铐上飞机
drop you off in jail and take you to the plane in chains.
了解吗? 了解 你先请
Understand? Perfectly. After you.
我觉得她有手铐
I think she has handcuffs.
希望如此
I do hope so.
不是下太多雨 就是不下雨!
他把缺水怪到全球暖化 他们说冰河都融化了
He blames the water shortage on global warming.
你好 卡洛斯? 卡洛斯
Hello, Carlos? Carlos.
你好吗? 政府一直在加税... 你好吗?
天晓得他们几时会想办法
这是掌管全国警察的上校
The Colonel who heads the National Police.
我阿妈 愿她安息 告诉我...
我没钱会打给你吗? 她什么都告诉我
而且她会托梦给我
她告诉我...
她告诉我:买一辆计程车
我们有订房
We have a reservation.
- 你好吗? - 很好 谢谢
- Cmo est? - Very well, thank you.
- 姓名? - 费姿
- Your name? - Miss Fields.
你哪儿也别想去　杀死我呀
You're going nowhere. So shoot me.
我宁愿住太平间
I'd rather stay in a morgue.
我们的身份是休假的老师 住这里符合我们的身份
We are teachers on sabbatical. This fits our cover.
才怪 上车
No, it doesn't. Get in.
上车
Get in!
我们是休假的老师
我们中了彩票
恭喜了 我能效劳吗?
请跟我来
Follow me, please.
让我带您参观房间
May I show you your room, senor?
不用 谢了
No, it's fine. Thank you.
我找不到...
I can't find the, um...
文具
The stationery.
过来帮我找
Will you come and help me look?
我们受邀参加一场派对
You've been invited to a party.
我不知道这里有朋友
I didn't know we had any friends here.
绿色星球
Greene Planet.
你不来?
You're not coming?
我要和上校喝酒
I'm having a drink with my friend the Colonel.
待会见
I'll see you there later.
你知道我有多生自己的气吗?
Do you know how angry I am at myself?
我无法想像
I can't imagine.
你一定气炸了
You must be furious.
你想参加一场派对吗?
Do you want to go to a party?
派对?
A party?
可是我没有礼服穿
But I have nothing to wear.
我们会想办法
We'll fix that.
(绿色星球 慈善基金会)
我知道你的真名比较好
It might be useful to know your real name.
费姿
Fields.
就是费姿
Just Fields.
那就是费姿吧
Fields it is, then.
地球的生态环境愈变愈糟
We are in a spiral of environmental decline.
自从1945年...地球有17%的植栽表面...
Since 1945, 17% of the planet's vegetated surface
已经无法恢复原貌
has been irreversibly degraded.
提亚计划只是绿色星球打造的...
The Tierra Project is just one small part of a global network of Eco Parks
全球生态公园的一小部分
that Greene Planet has created
目的是拯救濒临瓦解的地球
to rejuvenate a world on the verge of collapse.
希望今晚各位也能成为一分子
I hope that tonight you make the decision to be part of that.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
大家玩得开心
And have fun.
- 恭喜 - 谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
说得真好 恭喜了
Excellent speech and congratulations.
你说得很好 多明尼克
Wonderful speech, Dominic.
我们需要你　谢谢
We need you here. Thank you.
费姿 邦德 我朋友卡洛斯
Miss Fields, Mr. Bond, my friend Carlos.
幸会　女士
Pleased to meet you. Ma'am.
马西斯把你的事都告诉我了
Mr. Bond, Mathis has spoken a great deal about you.
我管辖的警力可以任你差遣
I want you to know my entire police force is at your disposal.
那真是太好了
Well, that could be very useful.
国民要花一半薪资...
You know, there are people in this country spending half their paycheck
来买干净的水
just to get clean water.
你有什么看法?
What do you think of that?
问题出在玻利维亚政府
The Bolivian government is the problem.
他们滥伐树木
They cut down the trees,
当水和土壤被冲刷到海里还装蒜
then act surprised when the water and the soil wash out to sea.
我完全同意 希望这点钱能帮忙
I couldn't agree more. I hope this figure is to your liking.
亲爱的 别开玩笑了
Chri, you shouldn't tease.
告诉他们你在波多西买的土地
Why don't you tell them about all the land you bought up outside Potos?
幸会了 失陪一下
It's been a pleasure. Will you excuse me?
没问题
Of course.
伐木权...
Somehow the logging rights
都被滥伐树木的集团买走
went to a multinational corporation that cut down the forests,
都是政府把土地卖给绿色星球以后
but only after our last government sold the land to Greene Planet.
我有没有说错呢?
Or have I got my facts crossed?
你说错了
Yes, I think you did.
失陪
You'll excuse us?
真美好的夜晚
What a wonderful night.
你害我损失一大笔钱
You just cost me quite a bit of money, darling.
原则是买不到的
You can't put a price on integrity.
我可以试试看
I can try.
哦!
Oh!
谢谢
Thank you.
你不只是跑来扫我的兴吧
Tell me you didn't drop by tonight just to piss on my parade.
我看你是想要将军的人头吧
Or are you still after this General's head for your mantel?
两者皆是
A little of both.
告诉我将军在哪里 也许你就不会再失去投资者
Tell me where Medrano is and maybe you won't lose any more investors.
你真让我很难过
You are really breaking my heart,
为了他陷害我
choosing an insect like that over me.
你想把我推下去吗?
Are you going to throw me over?
你喝了酒
No. You've been drinking,
也许是不小心滑倒
so maybe you slipped.
你会很想我的
Oh. Just think how much you'd miss me.
你们好
Good evening.
你在这里
There you are.
请恕我失陪
Would you excuse me?
邦德先生
Mr. Bond.
欢迎大驾光临
What a pleasure.
这小妞很难搞 在达到目的之前...
Well, careful with this one. She won't go to bed with you
她不会和你上床
unless you give her something she really wants.
不过她的床上功夫...
It's a shame because she's really quite stunning
真不是盖的
once you get her on her back.
可惜你的床上功夫不怎么样
I wish I could say the feeling was mutual.
抱歉 我们得走了
I'm sorry, Mr. Greene, but we have to go.
我的朋友都叫我多明尼克
Please. My friends call me Dominic.
那是一定的
I'm sure they do.
你对邦德了解多少?
How much do you know about Bond, Camille?
听说他是个大灾难
Because he's rather a tragic case.
就连英国情报局也管不了他
As Ml6 says, he's difficult to control.
只要和他牵扯的人都非死即伤
Nice way of saying that everything he touches seems to wither and die.
我们走吧
Shall we?
你可要小心一点
Doesn't bode well for you, I'm afraid.
不过你们倒是天生一对
You two do make a charming couple, though.
因为你们都是...该怎么说?
You're both... What's the expression?
瑕疵品
Damaged goods.
天啊!
Oh, my gosh!
真是对不起
I'm so sorry.
放轻松点 别坏我的事
Come on, lighten up. You're cramping my style.
你是英国情报员
So it's British intelligence now.
你要我做什么?
What the hell do you want from me?
给我看多明尼克的提亚计划
You're gonna show me Dominic Greene's Tierra Project.
你行吗? 我有选择吗?
Are you up to it? Do I have a choice?
你想要吗?
Do you want one?
你这个人超霸道的
There's something horribly efficient about you.
这算是称赞吗?
Is that a compliment?
格林在警方有朋友
Well, what's the bet that Dominic Greene has friends in the police force?
留在车上
Stay here.
晚上好
请出示证件
请打开后车厢
你为什么要我这么做?
Now, why would you want me to do that?
把他抬出来!
快点!
他在动
快开枪!
马西斯?
Mathis?
市区另一边有医院
There's a hospital on the other side of town.
拜托
Please.
待在我身边
Stay with me.
待在这里
Stay here, please.
求求你
Please.
过来
Come here.
没事了
It's okay.
好多了
That's better.
不痛了
That doesn't hurt.
马西斯是你的假名吗?
Is Mathis your cover name?
对
Yes.
不是很好 对吧?
Not a very good one, is it?
我们原谅对方了吗?
Do we forgive each other?
我不该丢下你一个人
I shouldn't have left you alone.
维丝普
Vesper.
她为你付出一切
She gave everything for you.
原谅她
Forgive her.
也原谅你自己
Forgive yourself.
你是这样对待朋友的吗?
Is that how you treat your friends?
他不会在乎的
He wouldn't care.
走吧
Let's go.
外交部长要见你
The Foreign Secretary's asking to see you.
我不知道什么?
What don't I know?
马西斯在玻利维亚遭到射杀
Rene Mathis has been shot dead in Bolivia.
警方说凶手是邦德
The police claim it was Bond.
我能效劳吗?
你付他多少钱?
How much did you pay him?
他本来要你 我用车抵押
Well, he wanted you, but I left him the car as collateral.
他出卖我们会赚更多钱
He'll make much more when he sells us out.
好
Right.
看看这玩意能不能飞
Let's see if this thing'll fly.
这里
Here.
我的资料说这里什么都没有
All the information I found said there was nothing of value there,
格林的地质学家却说有
but Greene's geologist had proof that there was.
听说你是玻利维亚情报局干员
My sources tell me you're Bolivian Secret Service,
或者曾经是
or used to be,
你为了潜入格林的组织跟他上床
and that you infiltrated Greene's organization by having sex with him.
- 你觉得不对吗? - 一点都不会
- That offends you? - No, not in the slightest.
你为什么对格林有兴趣?
So what's your interest in Greene?
他想要杀死我的朋友
Amongst other things, he tried to kill a friend of mine.
- 一个女人?  - 对
- A woman? - Yes.
不过不是你想的那样
But it's not what you think.
她是你妈妈?
Your mother?
她喜欢这么想
She likes to think so.
下面那是什么?
What's that down there?
落水洞
That's a sinkhole.
这附近有好几个
There are a few around here.
我只想说 我和格林不是...
Just for the record, I wasn't with Greene for my...
目标锁定 将目标击落
该死!
Damn it!
我们甩掉他们了
I think we lost him!
秃鹰 这是马尔凯蒂
目标在300度 10公里外
他来得很快
He's coming fast!
他就在你后面
He's right behind you!
来! 穿上去!
Here. Put that on!
快点!
Come on!
卡蜜儿!
Camille!
玻利维亚警方说邦德被拦下
According to the Bolivians, it was a routine stop,
然后开枪射死两名警察
and when they discovered Mathis' body, Bond disarmed and shot them.
现在没有目击证人
Of course, there are no witnesses to prove otherwise.
我要证据 不能就这样去
I need something. I can't go in there unarmed.
抱歉 没有证据
I'm sorry. There's nothing.
请进
Come in.
又有什么藉口? 邦德成了法盲了?
What's today's excuse? That Bond is legally blind?
不是的
No, Minister.
我不说你也知道首相很生气
I don't think I need to tell you how upset the PM is.
恕我直言 首相有我的电话
With respect, the PM has my direct line.
他想跟你讲话就会打给你
And he'd have used it if he'd wanted to speak to you.
抱歉 局势改变了
I'm sorry, M. Things have changed.
我们和盟友有很长的讨论
We've had long discussions with our cousins.
格林先生的兴趣和我们不谋而和
Mr. Greene's interests and ours now align.
他是世上...
Minister, this man is a major player
最危险的组织的主使
in one of the most dangerous organizations...
我们根本没听过这组织
We've never even heard of.
外交政策不能根据直觉而定
Foreign policy cannot be conducted on the basis of hunches and innuendo.
给我们时间收集证据
Then give us time to gather enough evidence
好让你做出正确的决定
so you can make informed decisions.
好吧
Fine.
假设你说的对 格林是个坏蛋
Say you're right. Say Greene is a villain.
要是我们不跟坏蛋打交道
If we refused to do business with villains,
我们就没有贸易伙伴
we'd have almost no one to trade with.
世界的石油短缺
The world's running out of oil, M.
俄国不肯跟我们做生意
The Russians aren't playing ball.
中美瓜分剩下的存量
The Americans and Chinese are dividing up what's left.
是非对错并不重要
Right or wrong doesn't come into it.
我们非得这么做不可
We're acting out of necessity.
邦德失去控制
Bond is running wild.
谁晓得他没有叛变?
Who's to say he hasn't been turned?
把他叫回来
Pull him in
不然美国佬就会杀死他
or the Americans will put him down.
我找到出口了
I think I found a way out.
你冷到发抖
You're freezing.
我没事
I'm fine.
格林有什么你要的?
So what is it that Greene has that you want?
跟格林无关 是马卓诺将军 他在海地碰面的人
It's not Greene. It's Medrano, the man he met in Haiti.
我父亲曾经在他麾下服役
My father worked for the military junta.
他是个冷血无情的人
He was a very cruel man,
但是他是我父亲
but he was my father.
我小时候
When I was a small child
反叛军派马卓诺到我家
the opposition sent general Medrano to our house.
他杀死我父亲
He shot my father.
强暴我妈妈和姐姐
He did things to my mother and my sister
然后在我面前把她们勒死
and then strangled them while I watched.
我还太小 逃过一劫
I was too young to be any trouble,
他只对我笑一笑
so he just smiled at me
然后就放火烧了我家
and set the house on fire.
他在我身上留下疤痕
He left his mark.
当我把你从船上拉下来...
So when I pulled you off the boat...
我等那一刻等了好多年
I waited years for that chance.
对不起
I apologize.
我们都在利用格林对付别人
It seems we're both using Greene to get to somebody.
你失去心爱的人?
You lost somebody?
是的
I did, yes.
你逮到凶手没?
You catch whoever did it?
不
No.
还没有
Not yet.
逮到告诉我
Tell me when you do.
我想知道那种感觉
I'd like to know how it feels.
我们该走了
We should go.
好了吗?
You ready?
他们用了炸药
They used dynamite.
这里以前是河床
This used to be a riverbed.
格林要的不是石油
Greene isn't after the oil.
而是水源
He wants the water.
我们不能放着不管
We can't leave it like this.
这只是一座水坝 他要造成旱灾 他还会盖更多水坝
It's one dam. He's creating a drought. He'll have built others.
尊夫人留言给您
Excuse me, sir. Your wife left a message.
那位英国女士把这个留给你
The English woman, she left it for you this morning.
- 谢谢你　- 不客气
- Thank you. - My pleasure.
那是什么?
What is it?
你介意在这里等吗?
Would you mind waiting down here?
我到外面等
I'll be outside.
原来她是这个意思
So that's what she meant.
希望你们信任这些人
I hope you can trust these men.
请稍等 是坦纳
Just a moment. It's Tanner.
请说
Yes?
我们在楼下拦住那女孩
We've got the girl downstairs.
她说抱歉 这不是她的事
She says to tell you she's sorry but this is not her fight.
没错 放她走
It isn't. Let her go.
她跟我们无关
She isn't our concern.
我很失望
Well, I'm disappointed.
是吗?
You are?
美国佬答应给你们多少石油?
How much oil did the Americans promise you?
这跟石油无关
This isn't about oil.
很好 因为没有石油
Well, that's good, because there isn't any.
这跟信任有关
It's about trust.
你说你的动机不是复仇
You said you weren't motivated by revenge.
我的动机是任务
I'm motivated by my duty.
不对
No.
无法平复的愤怒...
I think you are so blinded by inconsolable rage
已让你变的冷血
that you don't care who you hurt.
若你无法分辨敌我 就该停职
When you can't tell your friends from your enemies, it's time to go.
你可以告诉她没有石油
You might like to tell her your theory about there being no oil.
她的肺部全都是石油
Her lungs are full of it.
- 这是格林干的 - 没错 但是为什么?
- It was Greene. - No doubt. But why?
他只是杀错人了 为什么要杀她?
It's just misdirection. I mean, why her, Bond?
她只负责送你回英国 她在办公室工作
She was just supposed to send you home. She worked in an office,
整理报告
collecting reports.
看看你是多有魅力
Look how well your charm works, James.
她们为了你什么都肯做
They'll do anything for you, won't they?
有多少女人因你而死?
How many is that now?
你被停职 等待接受调查
You're removed from duty and suspended pending further investigation.
把武器交出来 跟他们走
You'll give whatever weapons you have to these men and leave with them now.
费姿展现无比的勇气
Miss Fields showed true bravery.
报告一定要提到这一点
I want that mentioned in your report.
你和我必须完成调查
Now you and I need to see this through.
你哪儿都去不了
There's nowhere to go.
有人下令看到你格杀勿论
There's a capture or kill order out on you.
谁会这么做?
Who would have done that?
夫人? 查出他去哪里
Ma'am? Find out where he's going.
他有线索　但是中情局...
He's on to something. Ma'am, the CIA is insisting...
我才不甩中情局和他们的假证据
I could give a shit about the CIA or their trumped-up evidence.
他是我的情报员 我信任他
He's my agent, and I trust him.
快点
Go on.
上车
Get in.
你要开枪杀我吗?
Are you gonna try and shoot me?
我说上车
I said, get in.
你喝那玩意会杆菌中毒
You're gonna get botulism if you keep drinking that.
这是瓶装矿泉水
It's bottled water.
大概是来自附近溪流的水
It probably came from some stream just around the corner from here.
小朋友在里面尿尿
Bunch of little kids peeing in it.
所以我才吃辣椒
That's why I eat the peppers.
我只想说
Well, all I'm saying is
这里什么都不能信
You can't trust a damn thing around here.
你应该直接说"中情局"
You know, you should just answer, "CIA," Felix.
就连计程车司机都知道
A taxi driver told me where the office was.
我们这么好找
Well, if we're so easy to find, James,
你应该来一趟
you really should come visit.
也许你应该多出门走走
Or maybe you should come out and see some more of the city.
听说你变得像南美洲人了
I heard a rumor you'd gone native.
费利克斯
Felix.
没有可卡因或共产党
You know, I was just wondering what South America would look like
不知道南美洲会变成怎样
if nobody gave a damn about coke or communism.
我很佩服你们把这地方搞成这样
It's always impressed me the way you boys have carved this place up.
英国人这么说算是称赞
I'll take that as a compliment coming from a Brit.
你确定你站在对的一边吗?
Are you sure you're playing with the right side?
政权每星期换一次
Regimes change once a week down here.
马卓诺不会比别人更腐败
Medrano'll be no dirtier than the next guy.
所以我才喜欢美国情报局
Oh, you see, that's what I like about U.S. Intelligence.
你们肯和任何人合作
You'll lie down with anybody.
包括你 兄弟 包括你
Including you, brother. Including you.
你们被耍了
Do you know you're being played?
格林会把这地方榨干
Dominic Greene's gonna suck this place dry, and then he's gonna move on,
让你们留下来 收拾烂摊子
and you're gonna be left picking up the broken crockery.
天下没有白吃的午餐
What can I tell you? There's no such thing as a free lunch.
我觉得你没有...
Well, you see, Felix, I don't think you're half as cynical
这么无情
as you make out to be.
你又不了解我
You don't know me.
为什么? 因为你带了人来?
Why? Just because you didn't come alone?
我有多少时间?
How long have I got?
30秒
Thirty seconds.
时间还真不充裕
Well, that doesn't give us a lot of time, does it?
马卓诺得先贿赂军方和警方
Medrano can't move until he pays off the army and the police chief.
格林正在带钱去给他
Greene's bringing him his money now.
沙丘旅馆
A hotel called La Perla de las Dunas
就在沙漠中间
in the desert.
谢了
Thank you, Felix.
快走吧
James, move your ass.
趴下! 趴下! 快!
Get down! Get down, now!
快走! 快走!
Move it! Move it!
怎么回事? 你跟他说什么?
What the hell happened? What did you tell him?
我们同意的事
Just what we agreed.
旅馆的保安有问题吗?
没有
那是电池 整间旅馆都靠它发电
其实很讨厌
听起来很不安全...
您需要什么 我能效劳吗?
问得好 来杯饮料吧
您要喝什么?
啤酒
一杯啤酒 您呢?
不用 走吧
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
枪膛卡住了
The slide's caught.
你也应该检查你的枪
Maybe you should check your own.
我会的
I will.
你杀过人吗?
Have you ever killed someone?
你接受的训练...
Your training will tell you that when the adrenaline kicks in
会让你冷静
you should compensate.
不过这次没用
But part of you is not gonna believe the training
因为你要报仇
because this kill is personal.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
只要开一枪
You only need one shot.
一枪毙命
Make it count.
他来了
笨蛋
欧元
In euros,
完全照你的要求
as requested.
美元贬值得太厉害了
The dollar isn't what it once was.
都是战争害的
The cost of war.
我们不能再容忍...
I am afraid that the corruption in this current government
政府的腐败
can no longer be tolerated.
我的钱呢?
And mine?
你得先签署土地让渡书
Right after you sign over my land.
拿到我的套房
我的第一个官方政策
My first official act.
还有这一份
And this, if you would.
这是什么?
What is this?
从这一刻开始
As of this moment,
我的组织拥有贵国六成的水源
my organization owns more than 60% of Bolivia's water supply.
这份合约规定你的新政府...
So this contract states that your new government
必须让我们成为水电供应商
will use us as utilities provider.
这比我们付的钱多两倍
This is double what we are paying now.
那就别签
Well, then don't sign it.
不过你要了解我和我的伙伴
But you should know something about me and the people I work with.
我们和左派或右派合作
We deal with the left or the right,
也和独裁者或自由派合作
with dictators or liberators.
要是目前的总统答应我的要求
If the current president had been more agreeable,
我就不会跟你合作
I wouldn't be talking to you.
要是你决定不签的话
So, if you decide not to sign,
你就会死得很惨
you will wake up with your balls in your mouth
你的替代者会站在你旁边
and your willing replacement standing over you.
不信的话就开枪杀死我
If you doubt that, then shoot me,
把钱拿走 然后好好睡一觉
take that money and have a good night's sleep.
你和我有相同的朋友
You and I had a mutual friend.
你的表情跟你妈当时一模一样
这一次 你也跑不掉的
听似你身边又少了一个人
Sounds like you just lost another one.
别过来
Not this way. Not this way.
我不行了
I can't. I can't.
过来
Come here.
你是怎么说的?
Like you said,
"深呼吸"
"Take a deep breath.
"一枪毙命"
"Make it count."
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
快点!
Come on!
在这里等
Wait here.
你答应要...
You promised that you'd...
放你走?
Let you go?
我回答了你的问题
I answered your questions.
也告诉你关于量子的事
I told you what you wanted to know about Quantum.
没错
Yes, you did,
你的伙伴也知道
and your friends'd know that
他们会追杀你
so they're probably looking for you.
好消息是 你人在沙漠中
But the good news is, you're in the middle of a desert.
拿去
Here.
我打赌你要走30公里才会想要喝
I bet you make it 20 miles before you consider drinking that.
再见 格林先生
Goodbye, Mr. Greene.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我的荣幸
It's my pleasure.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事
Fine.
不过我一直在想: 他死了
But I keep thinking, "He's dead.
现在该怎么办?
"Now what?"
我们看到的水坝
Well, the dam we saw will have to come down,
必须被毁掉
and there'll be others, too.
搞不好格林的手下能帮忙
Someone who worked for Greene might be of help.
这主意不赖
Not a bad idea.
你想他们现在睡得着吗?
Do you think they'll be able to sleep now?
死人应该不担心别人报仇
I don't think the dead care about vengeance.
我很想放你自由
I wish I could set you free.
但你被禁在心牢
But your prison is in there.
(俄罗斯 卡赞)
好 能活下去要我怎样都行
Fine. Anything for an easy life.
坐下来
Sit down.
给我坐下来!
Sit down!
没关系
It's okay, baby.
你是加拿大人?
You're Canadian?
你替加拿大情报局做事?
You work in Canadian intelligence?
没关系 我知道
It's all right. I know you do.
因为你认识这个人
And knowing this man,
所以你必须交出机密文件
I'd guess you have access to some very sensitive material
不然他就有生命危险
which you're gonna be forced to give up.
你很爱他
His life will be threatened,
所以你不会犹豫
and because you love him, you won't hesitate.
很美的项链
It's a beautiful necklace.
是他送你的吗?
Did he give it to you?
我也有一条
I have one just like it.
他送给我一个朋友
He gave it to a friend of mine,
和我很亲密的朋友
someone very close to me.
你叫什么?
Your name is?
珂伦　珂伦
Corrine. Corrine.
我要你马上离开
Corrine, I suggest you leave now.
请你的上司调查双面间谍
You contact your people, and you tell them to check their seals.
你们局里有内鬼
They have a leak.
请你马上去
Do it now, please.
我和他还有未了的恩怨
This man and I have some unfinished business.
谢谢
Thank you.
求求你
Please.
给我个痛快
Make it quick.
他还活着?
Is he still alive?
对
He is.
我很吃惊
I'm surprised.
你找到你要找的吗?
Did you find what you were looking for?
找到了 很好
Yes. Good.
我猜你不会后悔
I assume you have no regrets.
不会
I don't.
你呢?
What about you?
当然不会 这样太不专业了
Of course not. That would be unprofessional.
他们发现格林死在...
They found Greene dead
玻利维亚沙漠
in the middle of the Bolivian desert, of all places.
后脑勺两个弹孔
Two bullets in the back of his skull.
胃部还有汽油
They found motor oil in his stomach.
你知道这件事吗?
Does that mean anything to you?
真希望我能帮忙
Wish I could help.
我和美国佬把事情搞定了
You'll be glad to know, I straightened things out with the Americans.
你的朋友升职了 他取代了毕恩
Your friend Leiter's been promoted. He replaced Beam.
做的对的人保住他的工作
Well, then the right people kept their jobs.
应该是这样吧
Something like that.
恭喜 你是对的
Congratulations. You were right.
关于什么?
About what?
关于维丝普
About Vesper.
夫人
Ma'am.
邦德
Bond,
我需要你回来
I need you back.
我从来没有离开过
I never left.